<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Uncategorized &#8211; Brown Counseling</title>
	<atom:link href="https://browncounseling.biz/category/uncategorized/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://browncounseling.biz</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://browncounseling.biz/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/cropped-anchor-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Uncategorized &#8211; Brown Counseling</title>
	<link>https://browncounseling.biz</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title></title>
		<link>https://browncounseling.biz/604-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zain Saeed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://browncounseling.biz/?p=604</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How to Choose the best essay help How can I get essay help? Your research skills will be put to the test! An experienced academic writing consultant will examine your writing and provide helpful suggestions regarding the original draft of the client. Utilize this advice to improve your essay before submitting it to your professor! [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>
 How to Choose the best essay help<br />
</h1>
<p>
 How can I get essay help? Your research skills will be put to the test! An experienced academic writing consultant will examine your writing and provide helpful suggestions regarding the original draft of the client. Utilize this advice to improve your essay before submitting it to your professor! With essay help from an academic writing expert You can write an outstanding piece that will amaze your audience and earn you grades you&#8217;re proud of!
</p>
</p>
<p>
 You can improve your writing if you are like most students. If you require assistance with your homework, or just struggling with an essay because of a grammatical error, a writing professional can assist. Professional writers know all about writing that is free of plagiarism and know how important it is to establish an academic foundation for writing. If you have any questions regarding your writing, get in touch with an essay consultant. They can provide you with useful and educational tools to help you improve your academic writing skills. Do not let poor writing influence your essays! Get in touch with a professional writer today!
</p>
</p>
<p>
 Professional Academic Essay WritersTo become a professional academic writer you will require a high-quality academic writing service. You&#8217;ll learn valuable techniques and strategies from top essay writers. You&#8217;ll also receive personalized feedback and suggestions for improving your writing. You can also get expert academic assistance with one-on-one counseling. Get help with writing your essay today!
</p>
</p>
<p>
 Effective CommunicationA proficient essay writer can effectively communicate with clients. Effective communication will ensure that your communication is informative and has a positive impact. While working with clients, professional writers will keep you informed about the progress of your project. You can stay in touch with your writer by sharing information regarding the project as well as your thoughts. Your writer will be able do their best work if you communicate clearly <a href="https://www.affordable-papers.net/">how long does it take to type 5 pages</a> and professionally.
</p>
</p>
<p>
 Send us your top-quality essay. An essayist won&#8217;t be able to give you professional essay help if you don&#8217;t give them what they&#8217;re looking for. Tell your writer about your plans for the assignment before you send it. Your deadline is your deadline.
</p>
</p>
<p>
 Professional Essay Help There are essay helpers out there who only write one way and are not equipped to write essays. This is a waste of time and money. The best solution is to seek professional help with your essay online. It is important to ensure that the company provides detailed instructions for your assignment and that you keep in touch with their writers team.
</p>
</p>
<p>
 Choose Your Online Essay Helper carefully: There are companies out there that offer inexpensive essay helpers. These companies often employ inexperienced staff who aren&#8217;t aware of how different types of essays perform. You can review the company&#8217;s track record to discover how many students they have helped in the past. Ask around to see whether there are any experts who can help you with your essay that you can ask.
</p>
</p>
<p>
 Assistance with writing essays can be obtained from many different companies. It&#8217;s best to read through all the terms of service of various firms to ensure that you understand exactly what you&#8217;re getting when you choose them. Ask questions and conduct a thorough search to locate the essay writing assistance you need. You should select the top essay writing service online to ensure you are pleased with the speed and quality of your essay writing assistance. You can get the best customer service online so you can be certain that you won&#8217;t be disappointed.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Journal Prompts</title>
		<link>https://browncounseling.biz/writing-therapy-using-a-pen-and-paper-to-enhance-personal-growth/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zain Saeed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 16:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://browncounseling.biz/?p=571</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Writing Ideas &#38; Journal Prompts The following ideas and writing prompts are great ways to continue your journaling practice or to get yourself “unstuck” if you’re not sure what to write about next. For instance, you could try the five writing exercises from this blog: Writing a letter to yourself Writing letters to others Writing a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Writing Ideas &amp; Journal Prompts</h2>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-19724 entered lazyloaded" title="Journaling with Photographs" src="https://positive.b-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/writing-therapy-example.jpg" alt="Journaling with Photographs writing therapy" width="300" height="210" data-lazy-src="https://positive.b-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/writing-therapy-example.jpg" data-ll-status="loaded" />The following ideas and writing prompts are great ways to continue your journaling practice or to get yourself “unstuck” if you’re not sure what to write about next.</p>
<p>For instance, you could try the five writing exercises from this blog:</p>
<ol>
<li>Writing a letter to yourself</li>
<li>Writing letters to others</li>
<li>Writing a poem</li>
<li>Free writing (just writing everything that comes to mind)</li>
<li>Mind mapping (drawing mind maps with your main problem in the middle and branches representing different aspects of your problem)</li>
</ol>
<p>If those ideas don’t get your juices flowing, try these prompts:</p>
<ul>
<li>Journaling with Photographs – choose a personal photo and use your journal to answer questions like “What do you feel when you look at these photos?” or “What do you want to say to the people, places, or things in these photos?”</li>
<li>Timed Journal Entries – decide on a topic and set a timer for 10 or 15 minutes to write continuously.</li>
<li>Sentence Stems – these prompts are the beginnings of a sentence that encourage meaningful writing, such as “The thing I am most worried about is…”, “I have trouble sleeping when…”, and “My happiest memory is…”</li>
<li>List of 100 – these ideas encourage the writer to create lists of 100 based on prompts like “100 Things That Make Me Sad,” “100 Reasons to Wake Up in the Morning,” and “100 Things I Love” (Farooqui, 2016).</li>
</ul>
<p>Psychologist Margarita Tartakovsky provides a handy list of 30 prompts (2014). Some of these include:</p>
<ol>
<li>My favorite way to spend the day is…</li>
<li>If I could talk to my teenage self, the one thing I would say is…</li>
<li>Make a list of 30 things that make you smile.</li>
<li>The words I’d like to live by are…</li>
<li>I really wish others knew this about me…</li>
<li>What always brings tears to your eyes?</li>
<li>Using 10 words, describe yourself.</li>
<li>Write a list of questions to which you urgently need answers.</li>
</ol>
<p>If you’re still on the lookout for more prompts, try the lists outlined here.</p>
<p><a name="exercises-writing-therapy"></a></p>
<h2>Exercises and Ideas to Help You Get Started</h2>
<p>As great as the benefits of therapeutic journaling sound, it can be difficult to get started. After all, it can be a challenge to start even the most basic of good habits!</p>
<p>If you’re wondering how you begin, read on for some tips and exercises to help you start your regular writing habit.</p>
<p>This list of ten handy tips can help get you started:</p>
<ul>
<li>Start writing about where you are in your life at this moment.</li>
<li>For five to ten minutes just start writing in a “stream of consciousness.”</li>
<li>Start a dialogue with your inner child by writing in your subdominant hand.</li>
<li>Cultivate an attitude of gratitude by maintaining a daily list of things you appreciate, including uplifting quotes.</li>
<li>Start a journal of self-portraits.</li>
<li>Keep a nature diary to connect with the natural world.</li>
<li>Maintain a log of successes.</li>
<li>Keep a log or playlist of your favorite songs.</li>
<li>If there’s something you are struggling with or an event that’s disturbing you, write about it in the third person.</li>
<li>Develop your intuition and learn to listen to yourself (Hills, n.d.).</li>
</ul>
<p>If you’re still having a tough time getting started, consider trying a “mind dump.” This is a quick exercise that can help you get a jump start on therapeutic writing.</p>
<p>Researcher and writer Gillie Bolton suggests simply writing for six minutes (Pollard, 2002). Don’t pay attention to grammar, spelling, style, syntax, or fixing typos – just write. Once you have “dumped,” you can focus on a theme. The theme should be something concrete, like something from your childhood with personal value.</p>
<p>This exercise can help you ensure that your therapeutic journal entries go deeper than the more superficial diary or journal entries.</p>
<p>More prompts, exercises, and ideas to help you get started can be found at this link.</p>
<p><a name="home"></a></p>
<h2>A Take-Home Message</h2>
<p>In this piece, we went over writing therapy – what it is, how to do it, and how it can benefit you. I hope you learned something new from this piece, and I hope you will keep writing therapy in mind the next time you find yourself considering a visit to a therapist’s office.</p>
<p>Have you ever tried writing therapy? Would you try writing therapy? How do you think it would benefit you? Let us know your thoughts in the comments!</p>
<p>Thanks for reading, and happy writing!</p>
<p>We hope you enjoyed reading this article. Don’t forget to download our 3 Positive Psychology Exercises for free.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>And a Child Shall Lead Them</title>
		<link>https://browncounseling.biz/and-a-child-shall-lead-them/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zain Saeed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 16:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://browncounseling.biz/?p=121</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wpb-content-wrapper"><div class="vc_row wpb_row row top-row"><div class="vc_column_container col-md-12"><div class="wpb_wrapper vc_column-inner">
	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element " >
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<p>We can go our entire lives thinking that we have a pretty strong grip on reality – and that we in fact <em>do</em> know shiitake mushrooms from Shinola. However, we may be surprised that we don’t know Didley or anybody in his family. We have all seen the posts on social media in which people exclaim over and over that they were “now years old” when they found out that the two holes on the side of a Reynold’s wrap package are there to prevent the foil from becoming a shredded-up mess.  Or that the button (indentation) on the side of a milk carton is actually an indicator mechanism designed to let the consumer know when the milk is no longer fresh. Apparently, this button pops out, if you will, once the milk is spoiled. What???</p>
<p>Being completely flabbergasted as to how you have lived a number of years completely in the dark about something is one thing, but to be “educated” by a child is another.</p>
<p>Intelligent kids have been around for some time. My father once told me a story about a truck driver who was stuck at a viaduct because his truck didn’t pass the height restrictions. The trucker stood there bewildered. He even called on a few passers-by to see if anyone could help figure out his dilemma. Just when it seemed that the only answer was to retreat and go another way, a little boy came along and offered a suggestion. As the story goes, the boy looked at the trucker and said, “If you let the air out of the tires, that will lower the height of the truck just enough for it to pass through.” The trucker heeded this advice and was able to pass under the viaduct without damaging the top of the vehicle. Sometimes, it’s the simple things that leave us awestruck.</p>

		</div>
	</div>
</div></div></div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>They Will Be Alright</title>
		<link>https://browncounseling.biz/they-will-be-alright/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zain Saeed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 16:04:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://browncounseling.biz/?p=118</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wpb-content-wrapper"><div class="vc_row wpb_row row top-row"><div class="vc_column_container col-md-12"><div class="wpb_wrapper vc_column-inner">
	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element " >
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<p>imone Biles chose her mental health and well-being over the Olympic finals. She chose peace over gold medals. She chose herself over others. That is the attitude that every human being needs to take. Some of you may be thinking, <em>Isn’t that a little selfish?</em> The short answer is no. The more complex and detailed response is forthcoming, but to be direct – it is not selfish. It’s called self-preservation.</p>
<p>(<em>ESPN</em>)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Too many times, I have seen people remain in places for far too long. They remain stagnant and feel a sense of obligation. Why? Because <em>they</em> will be upset, or <em>they</em> will end up in a bind, or <em>they</em> will suffer some other form of disappointment over their personal choice to bow out gracefully. Well, guess what? <em>They</em> will be alright.</p>
<p>Who are <em>they</em>? The ones who want you to forego your own wants and needs so you can fulfill theirs.</p>
<p>Many of us have been erroneously taught to endure mistreatment and outright abuse at the hands of employers because being a “good” employee represents loyalty and dependability. Especially when we have the kind of job that comes with a great deal of responsibility. The position may seem glamorous to those on the outside looking in. But only the people who are walking a mile in those shoes truly know how much they can take.</p>
<p>The flack that Biles has received over her decision to withdraw from the Olympic finals is appalling. She has been called a “quitter” and a “disgrace to her country.” Like many of you, the criticism made me angry. I’m glad that she received such an outpouring of love and support from people (myself included) who understood her decision and respect her for it.  I sincerely hope that her decision inspired millions of people to follow her lead and protect their peace over people pleasing.</p>

		</div>
	</div>
</div></div></div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Social Media Trap</title>
		<link>https://browncounseling.biz/the-social-media-trap/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zain Saeed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 15:59:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://browncounseling.biz/?p=115</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wpb-content-wrapper"><div class="vc_row wpb_row row top-row"><div class="vc_column_container col-md-12"><div class="wpb_wrapper vc_column-inner">
	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element " >
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<p>It may be hard to believe, but I know several people who do not have social media (SM) profiles. That’s right – they are among us. I often wonder how the non-social media folks decided not to jump on the bandwagon. Did they somehow know that SM would one day govern their lives and they just couldn’t fathom such a travesty? Well, it may have been a conscious effort for some, but others may have had a different experience. It might have gone something like this: They came. They saw. They said, “No, thank you.”</p>
<p>Whatever the reason, this elite group (at least they are in my eyes) managed to outrun the trap. I know that “trap” is an interesting choice for a word, especially when I, like many other creators, rely on social media for the kind of exposure that is needed to get the word out about our work. That aside, I won’t lament about the “evils” of social media because that horse has been beaten to death and has long since been buried.</p>
<p>What I will say is this: For those of us who have chosen this life (i.e. Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, TikTok, etc.), these platforms have become an integral part of our existence. So much so, that we can barely let a day go by without checking in. It starts with a notification. We hear that bell, and everything around us stops. Classical conditioning at its finest. Pavlov would be so proud. Before we open that app, we think to ourselves,<em> let me check this right quick!</em> And that usually leads to us mindlessly scrolling our timelines. Sometimes it’s just for a moment – other times, we get caught up in a never-ending barrage of birthday wishes, anniversary shout outs, hearts, laughs, and thumbs ups</p>

		</div>
	</div>
</div></div></div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
